Jeff Brozena

jeff@brozena.net | +1 (570)335-8269

SUMMARY

An operator and teacher with 5+ years in strategic alignment/systems integration, software training, and change management at one of the country's largest privately-held Medicaid pediatric dental groups. With over 50,000 appointments seen per year and little chance for downtime, I stewarded the group from paper-based record-keeping to full digitization and was entrusted to set strategic direction, improve core business processes and lead complex change shortly before a cross-generational ownership transfer was expected. I leveraged software integration to catalyze systemic organizational change at scale.

My impact at this group was described positively as "like a crater" by its ownership.

EXPERIENCE

Penn State University - Research Support

Sep 2019 - present

- College of Information Sciences & Technology, Wellbeing and Health Innovation Lab
- Working to develop a conceptual and technical framework to detect mental health states using multi-modal data streams reflecting online activities.

The Smilist Management - Manager of Optimization

Feb 2018 — Aug 2018

- Process discovery, documentation, and re-engineering at a multi-site dental service organization.
- Conducted individual/group interviews and observed process to document and address systemic issues at their root cause after quickly establishing rapport with a variety of stakeholders.

Smiles 4 Keeps Pediatric Dentistry - Practice Operations

Aug 2012 - Nov 2017

- Responsible for a complete paper-to-digital transformation in the midst of a crossgenerational familial ownership transfer, resulting in an accurate third-party valuation of business.
- Spoke publicly at American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry, Pennsylvania Academy of Pediatric Dentistry on the subjects of digitization and compliant record-keeping.

Bedrock Technology - Technician

Jan 2012 — Aug 2012

Appek Mobile Apps - Project Manager

May 2011 — Dec 2012

Penn State University - Research Assistant

May 2009 — Jan 2010

 College of Information Sciences & Technology, Human-Computer Interaction Lab

Penn State University - Software Trainer

Aug 2007 — Dec 2009

AWARDS

Rock Ethics Stand Up Award, Penn State University

• Promoted to supervisory position in June, 2009.

Apr 2011

Emerging Scholars Fellowship, Active Minds, Inc.

Jan 2011

EDUCATION

Pennsylvania State University

Dec 2019

BS - Information Sciences & Technology

SKILLS

Leadership: Public speaking, Systems thinking, Whole systems management, Written & verbal clarity, Motivational interviewing, Situational leadership

Digital transformation: Software training, Transformational change, Change management, Strategic planning, Business analysis

Healthcare information technology (HIT): HIPAA compliance, Electronic data interchange (EDI), Electronic medical record (EMR), Analytics, SQL, Product management, Systems integration, Software integration, Electronic remittance advice (ERA), Clinical decision support

Program management: Process improvement, Project management, Process optimization, Process management, Lean Six Sigma, Kaizen

.....